Henry A. Grunwald Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings, 1940-2004 (Box 27-88)
  - Books
    - A Saint More or Less
      - Digital drafts and research files
        - Nov. 2001, mss85225_142_007
        - Nov. 2001, mss85225_142_008
        - Jan. 2002, mss85225_142_010
        - Mar. 2002, mss85225_142_009
      - l'Estoile, Pierre de, 1958 (Box 59)
      - Final proofs, 2003 (Box 59)
      - Foreign editions, 2004 (Box 59)
      - France, 1983-2000, (2 folders) (Box 60)
      - Frumkin, Robert, 1999 (Box 60)
      - Hatcher, Elizabeth, 1999 (Box 60)
      - Henri de Navarre, 2000 (Box 60)
      - Humanism, 1999 (Box 60)
      - Inns, 1999 (Box 60)
      - Medical, 1999-2003 (Box 60)
      - Medina, Kate, 2003, (2 folders) (Box 60)
      - Medina, Kate, 2003-2004 (Box 61)
      - Miracles, 1996-1999, (2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous research, 1998-1999, undated, (2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Montaigne, Michel de, 1999-2000 (Box 61)
      - Mousnier, Roland, undated (Box 61)
      - Nesbit, Lynn, 1999-2004 (Box 61)
      - Paperback edition, 2004 (Box 61)
      - Possession and exorcism, 1999 (Box 61)
      - Production, 2003 (Box 61)
      - Protestantism, 2000-2001 (Box 61)
      - Protestantism, 2000-2001 (Box 62)
      - Publications, 1953-2001 (Box 62)
      - Publicity, 2003-2004 (Box 62)
      - Rabelais, Francois, 1999 (Box 62)
      - Religion, 1999 (Box 62)
      - Religious processions, 1999 (Box 62)
      - Researchers, 1999 (Box 62)
      - Saint Theresa of Avila, 1999 (Box 62)
      - Saints, 1996-2003 (Box 63)
      - Sermons, 1999-2001 (Box 63)
      - Shapiro, Stephen, 1997-1998 (Box 63)
      - Solomon, Solange, 1999-2004, (2 folders) (Box 63)
      - Tavernier, Nicole, 1999-2000 (Box 63)
      - Timelines, 2000-2003 (Box 63)
      - Washburn, Sue, 2000-2003 (Box 63)
      - Witches, 1999-2001 (Box 64)
      - Women, 2000 (Box 64)
    - Twilight: Losing Sight, Gaining Insight
      - Acknowledgments, 1999 (Box 64)
      - Additions, 1998 (Box 64)
      - Alfred A. Knopf Inc., 1997-1999 (Box 64)
      - American Academy of Opthalmology, 1998 (Box 64)
      - American Academy of Optometry, 2000 (Box 64)
      - Artwork, undated (Box 64)
      - Audio books, 1999-2000 (Box 64)
      - Book parties, 1997-1999 (Box 65)
      - Book proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 65)
      - Book tour, 1999 (Box 65)
      - Books sent, 1999 (Box 65)
      - Community Services for the Blind and Partially Sighted, 2000 (Box 65)
      - Copyedited manuscript, 1999 (Box 65)
      - Correspondence, 1998-2000, (2 folders) (Box 65)
      - Correspondence, 1998-2000, (2 folders) (Box 66)
      - Dateline NBC, 2000 (Box 66)
      - Drafts, 1999, (2 folders) (Box 66)
      - Dunne, Cara, 1997-1998 (Box 66)
      - Events, 1999-2000 (Box 66)
      - Evolution, 1998 (Box 66)
      - Frank, Dan, 1998-1999 (Box 66)
      - Galley proofs, 1999 (Box 66)
      - Gass, Donald M., 1997-1998 (Box 67)
      - German special edition, 2000-2001 (Box 67)
      - Guyer, David, 1988-2000, (2 folders) (Box 67)
      - Jurich, Marilyn, 1998-1999 (Box 67)
      - Light, undated (Box 67)
      - The Lighthouse Inc., 1996-1998 (Box 67)
      - "Losing Sight," The New Yorker, 1996 (Box 68)
      - Lyndon Baines Johnson Presidential Library, 2000 (Box 68)
      - Macular degeneration, 1996-1997 (Box 68)
      - Medicare Vision Rehabilitation Coverage Act, 2000 (Box 68)
      - Mihm, Stephen, 1998 (Box 68)
      - Miscellany, 1998-2001 (Box 68)
      - Moorfields Eye Hospital, London, United Kingdom, 1999 (Box 68)
      - Nesbit, Lynn, 1997-1999 (Box 68)
      - The New Yorker letters, 1996-1998, (3 folders) (Box 68)
      - Opthalmology, 1982-2000 (Box 69)
      - Patinkin, Mandy, 1998 (Box 69)
      - People, 1998 (Box 69)
      - Perkins School for the Blind, Watertown, Mass., 2000 (Box 69)
      - Philosophy, undated (Box 69)
      - Psychology, undated, (2 folders) (Box 69)
      - Publicity, 1998-2003, (3 folders) (Box 70)
      - Research, 1987-1998, (2 folders) (Box 70)
      - Reviews and clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 70)
      - See notes, 1998 (Box 70)
      - Sources, 1999 (Box 70)
      - Stevenson, Nick, 1998-2000 (Box 71)
      - Sunness, Janet, 1998 (Box 71)
      - Talking points, 1999 (Box 71)
      - Titles, undated (Box 71)
      - Treatments, 1998-1999 (Box 71)
      - Tucker, Bonnie Poitras, undated (Box 71)
      - Visual, undated (Box 71)
      - "The Will to See," 1998, (3 folders) (Box 71)
      - Wills Eye Hospital Ball, 2000 (Box 71)
      - "Windows of the Soul," documentary, 2000 (Box 71)
      - Yannuzzi, Lawrence A., 1983-1999 (Box 71)
  - Journals
    - Jan.-Feb. 1986, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1986, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Mar. 1986, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Apr.-May 1986 (Box 72)
    - 1987, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Miscellany, undated, (3 folders) (Box 73)
  - Proposed projects
    - "Can Arabs Become Modern?" undated (Box 73)
    - Columbia Journalism Review interview, 1996 (Box 73)
    - Flat earthers, 1997 (Box 73)
    - Global Viewpoint, Log Angeles Times syndicate, 1992-1995 (Box 73)
    - Introduction to "Austrians in Exile, USA," by Siegwald Ganglmair, 1994 (Box 73)
    - Japanese television, 1993 (Box 73)
    - The Last Word, novel, 2004 (Box 73)
    - "Millenium" article, Time magazine, 1997-1998 (Box 73)
    - The New Yorker Europe piece, 2003 (Box 73)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1992-1994 (Box 74)
    - Quality magazine, 1982-1995 (Box 74)
    - Soul magazine
      - Digital files, proposal drafts and sample issue outlines, 1998-1999, mss85225_142_011
      - Paper files, general, 1996-1999, (8 folders) (Box 74)
      - Paper files, general, 1996-1999, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - World Monuments Fund, 1993 (Box 75)
  - Speeches
    - 1957, "Conformity," Phi Beta Kapa (Box 75)
    - 1973, Time fiftieth anniversary dinner, 22 Oct. (Box 75)
    - 1974, Century Club, 10 Jan. (Box 75)
    - 1975
      - "America at 200: Have We Kept Our Promise," New York University, 24 Apr. (Box 75)
      - Nightingale-Bamford School commencement address, 5 June (Box 75)
      - "Thoughts From a Western Trip," 18 Dec. (Box 75)
    - 1976, Time and Newsweek remarks before the board of directors, 18 Nov. (Box 75)
    - 1977
      - "The Mood of America," Update on America, Washington, D.C., 16 Oct. (Box 75)
      - Time, inc. creative conference, Bermuda, 12 July (Box 75)
      - Time staff dinner, 28 Nov. (Box 75)
    - 1978
      - Cronkite toast, Lord and Taylor Rose award, 1 Nov. (Box 75)
      - Penney-Missouri awards, 1 Nov. (Box 75)
      - Tax conference opening statement, Washington, D.C., 13 Sept. (Box 75)
    - 1979
      - Annual judicial conference, second judicial circuit, Buck Hill Falls, Penn., 27 May (Box 75)
      - Donovan, Grunwald, and Graves dinner, 30 May (Box 75)
      - Henry Kissinger dinner introductory remarks, 2 Oct. (Box 75)
      - Washington Star dinner, Washington, D.C., 13 Sept. (Box 75)
    - 1980
      - American Society of Magazine Editors intern lunch, 22 Aug. (Box 75)
      - Edmund Muskie introduction, Foreign Policy Association, 7 July (Box 75)
      - Fortune anniversary dinner, 4 Feb. (Box 75)
      - Fortune corporate communications seminar, 30 Mar. (Box 75)
      - Henry Kissinger Friars Club dinner, 3 May (Box 76)
      - Los Angeles businessmen lunch, 25 Feb. (Box 76)
      - Pringle lecture, Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, New York, N.Y., 12 May (Box 76)
      - Time Boston jubilee dinner, 10 Apr. (Box 76)
      - Time international sales conference, 1 July (Box 76)
    - 1981
      - American Association of Advertising Agencies, western region, 2 Oct. (Box 76)
      - Iona College commencement address, New Rochelle, N.Y., 7 June (Box 76)
      - National interests, Canada's Business Council, 14 Apr. (Box 76)
      - Ronald Reagan dinner, 6 Jan. (Box 76)
      - Time, inc. dinner, 18 Mar. (Box 76)
    - 1982
      - Association of National Advertisers conference, 8 Nov. (Box 76)
      - Chicago staff remarks, 9 Feb. (Box 76)
      - "How the Press Is Seen Today," Time, inc. public affairs conference, 22 Mar. (Box 76)
      - National Center for Citizen Involvement, 7 June (Box 76)
      - "The Press: From Hero to Villain," St. John's College, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1 Aug. (Box 76)
      - Society of the Silurians, Inc., dinner, 15 Nov. (Box 76)
      - "U.S. Foreign Policy: Ulysses vs. Matt Dillon," Foreign Policy Association, 13 Oct. (Box 76)
    - 1983
      - "The Art of Editing," American Society of Magazine Editors, 9 Dec. (Box 76)
      - Bennett College commencement address, Greensboro, N.C., 8 May (Box 76)
      - George Shultz introduction, Foreign Policy Association, 26 May (Box 76)
      - Life sales meeting, Cancun, Mexico, 20 Mar. (Box 76)
      - Newsweek fiftieth anniversary, 7 Feb. (Box 76)
    - 1984
      - Advertising Women of New York, 18 Sept. (Box 76)
      - Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture, New York University, New York, N.Y., 15 Nov. (Box 76)
      - People tenth anniversary, 27 June (Box 76)
      - Politics and power seminar, 27 July (Box 76)
      - Twentieth Century Fund, 8 Dec. (Box 76)
    - 1985
      - American Television and Communications Corporation conference, 7 Aug. (Box 76)
      - CM & D conference, 3 Sept. (Box 76)
      - "The Computer: For or Against the Humanities?" International Industrial conference, 18 Sept. (Box 76)
      - Corporate public affairs conference, Ponte Vedra, Fla., 4 Mar. (Box 76)
      - "Hopes and Fears in the Mid-Eighties," American Association of Advertising Agencies, 16 May (Box 76)
      - "How to Lose Friends and Influence Countries," New York Public Library, New York, N.Y., 2 Oct. (Box 77)
      - "In Praise of Magazines," Delacorte lecture, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 20 Mar. (Box 77)
      - Mikhail Gorbachev speech, Foreign Policy Association, 11 Oct. (Box 77)
      - "Nobody Loves the Press. Whom Does the Press Love?" Sports Illustrated staff, 3 Oct. (Box 77)
      - "The Press: Why You Can't Love It or Leave It," Case Western University commencement address, Cleveland, Ohio, 22 May (Box 77)
      - Time-Life Alumni Association, 4 Feb. (Box 77)
      - Time sales meeting, Carefree, Ariz. (Box 77)
      - Update on America, Washington, D.C., 24 Feb. (Box 77)
    - 1986
      - Arthur Burns introduction, Council on Foreign Relations, 6 Feb. (Box 77)
      - Center for Communication lunch honoring Punch Sulzberger, 15 Apr. (Box 77)
      - "Foreign Policy and the Press," International Women's Media conference, 14 Nov. (Box 77)
      - Time College Achievement Awards, 31 Mar. (Box 77)
      - Time-Life Books twentieth anniversary, 23 June (Box 77)
    - 1987
      - American Jewish Committee National Executive Council dinner, 31 Oct. (Box 77)
      - American Society of Magazine Editors conference, 20 Apr. (Box 77)
      - Henry Grunwald-Jason McManus dinner, 7 Oct. (Box 77)
      - "The Law and the Press: Uneasy Alliance," Harvard Law School Association, 27 Oct. (Box 78)
      - Panorama twenty-fifth anniversary speech, 7 Nov., (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Time board of directors speech, undated (Box 78)
      - Time question and answer session, 23 Mar. (Box 78)
      - William Colby and Stansfield Turner introduction, Council on Foreign Relations, 25 Mar. (Box 78)
    - 1988
      - American International School, Vienna, Austria, commencement address, 8 June (Box 78)
      - American Women's Association, 20 Apr. (Box 78)
      - "Austria: the Sound of Which Music?" University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minn., 12 Apr. (Box 78)
      - "Europe and the United States at the End of the Twentieth Century," Austrian Society for Foreign Policy and International Relations, 24 Mar. (Box 78)
      - "Gorbachev and the Failure of Marxism," Academic Society of Foreign Policy and International Relations, Innsbruck, Austria, 27 Oct., (2 folders) (Box 79)
      - "The Hidden Story of the 1980's," American Chamber of Commerce in Austria, 4 May (Box 79)
      - "How to Become an American," Austrian Association of American Studies, 11 Nov. (Box 79)
      - Imogen Cunningham exhibit remarks, Vienna, Austria, 30 June (Box 79)
      - "Looking East and West From Vienna," Council on Foreign Relations, 21 Nov. (Box 79)
      - Managers' lunch, Vienna, Austria, 15 Sept. (Box 79)
      - Masterdrawings from New York exhibition, Vienna, Austria, 28 Nov. (Box 79)
      - "The Presidential Election and the American Press," Press Club Concordia, Vienna, Austria, 22 Nov. (Box 79)
      - Ronald Reagan's Fourth of July message, American International School, Vienna, Austria, 2 July (Box 79)
      - Styrian Office of the American Chamber of Commerce in Austria, 27 Apr. (Box 79)
      - Thanksgiving remarks, Vienna, Austria, 23 Nov. (Box 79)
      - Worldnet inauguration, Krems, Austria, 5 Oct. (Box 79)
    - 1989
      - Alfred Grünwald Park dedication, Vienna, Austria, 29 Mar. (Box 79)
      - "American Foreign Policy: A New Administration in a Changing World," 10 Apr. (Box 80)
      - American Women's Club of Vienna, 4 Oct. (Box 80)
      - Amerika Haus re-opening, Vienna, Austria, 24 Oct. (Box 80)
      - "Are We Ready for the Post-Marxist World?" Board of International Broadcasting and Radio Free Europe, Munich, Germany, 16 May (Box 80)
      - B'nai Brith, 8 Nov. (Box 80)
      - Boyden group, Vienna, Austria, 15 Sept. (Box 80)
      - "The Challenge of the Information Age," European Media Symposium, Vienna, Austria, 21 May (Box 80)
      - Coca-Cola remarks, 30 Jan. (Box 80)
      - "Economic Prospects of the Bush Administration," Management Club, Vienna, Austria, 15 Mar. (Box 80)
      - Fulbright reception, 26 Sept. (Box 80)
      - "Global Change and Economic Adjustment," Club Internationale Wirtschaft, 21 June (Box 80)
      - Harvard Club of Vienna, 29 Sept. (Box 80)
      - Hewlett-Packard fiftieth anniversary, 28 Feb. (Box 80)
      - "The Information Revolution," Webster University, Vienna, Austria, 17 May (Box 80)
      - Jim Dine exhibition, Vienna, Austria, 11 Jan. (Box 81)
      - Kolingasse 4 memorial plaque, Vienna, Austria, 21 Oct. (Box 81)
      - Leonard Bernstein dinner, Vienna, Austria, 16 Sept. (Box 81)
      - "Lieber Augustin," the Rathaus, Vienna, Austria, 27 Jan. (Box 81)
      - "The Media and Culture," circa 4 Sept. (Box 81)
      - "Models of a Future Europe," conference at Amerika Haus, Vienna, Austria, 20 Nov. (Box 81)
      - "Models of a Future Europe," Creditanstalt International Advisory Board, 19 Nov. (Box 81)
      - St. Johann Club, Vienna, Austria, 1 Mar. (Box 81)
      - Salzburg Press Club, 24 Apr. (Box 81)
      - United States-Austria Air Services Agreement signing, 16 Mar. (Box 81)
      - "The U.S. and European Integration," 16 Nov. (Box 81)
    - 1990
      - "From Cold War to Baghdad - and Beyond," Foreign Policy Association, 26 Sept. (Box 81)
      - "Journalism and Diplomacy," Center for Communication, 8 May (Box 81)
      - "Journalism and Diplomacy," Time-Life Alumni Society, 4 Oct. (Box 82)
      - "A New World Order?" US-Austrian Chamber of Commerce, 30 Nov. (Box 82)
      - "The Post-Cold War World," New York University, New York, N.Y., 17 Apr. (Box 82)
      - Southampton College, Long Island, N.Y., 15 Sept. (Box 82)
      - "The World After the Cold War," American Council on Germany, 16 May, (2 folders) (Box 82)
      - World Press Freedom Committee, 8-10 Oct. (Box 82)
      - "The World Upside Down," World Affairs Council, 15 Sept. (Box 83)
    - 1991
      - "Eastern Europe," United States Council for International Business, 16 May, (5 folders) (Box 83)
      - "Eastern Europe," United States Council for International Business, 16 May, (5 folders) (Box 84)
      - Franz Vranitzky introduction, Johns Hopkins University School of Advanced International Studies, Washington, D.C., 10 Oct. (Box 84)
      - "Global Interdependence: the Challenge of a New World Marketplace," NeoCon, 11 June (Box 84)
      - Vaclev Havel greeting, convocation, New York University, New York, N.Y., 27 Oct. (Box 84)
    - 1992
      - "After Sovereignty," Royal Society for Arts, Manufactures and Commerce, 9 Mar. (Box 84)
      - "Fin de Siecle Thoughts About America," the Henkel Corporation, 11 Oct. (Box 84)
      - "Fin de Siecle: Ending or Beginning?" New York Public Library, New York, N.Y., 22 Jan., (2 folders) (Box 84)
      - "A Free Society of a Free Press?" Tufts University, Medford, Mass., 11 Apr., (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - 1993
      - "In Spite of Everything, the Press Must Be Free," World Press Freedom Day, Moscow, Russia, 3 May, (3 folders) (Box 85)
      - "The Press in the Post Cold War Era," Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 10 Feb. (Box 85)
    - 1994
      - "The New Information Age: Highway to Where?" Austrian Media Days, Vienna, Austria
        - Digital draft, 17 Sept., mss85225_142_012
        - Paper draft, 18 Oct., (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - "Self-Determination: Has it Gone Too Far?" Internationale Salzburg Association, Vienna, Austria
        - Digital draft, 26 Sept., mss85225_142_013
        - Paper draft, 21 Oct. (Box 86)
    - 1997
      - Bard College Music Festival benefit gala, Annandale-on-Hudson, N.Y., 3 Nov. (Box 86)
      - Carnegie Council speech, 14 Jan. (Box 86)
      - "Who's Afraid of Revolution?" Fortune Round Table, "Mastering Revolutionary Change," Baden Baden, Germany, 24 Sept. (Box 86)
    - Undated (Box 86)
  - Student writings
    - English, 1941-1942, undated (Box 87)
    - Essays, undated (Box 87)
    - Fiction, undated (Box 87)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 87)
    - Journalism, 1943 (Box 87)
    - Motion pictures, undated (Box 87)
    - New York University student newspapers, 1942-1944, (3 folders) (Box 87)
    - Outlines, undated (Box 88)
    - Philosophy, undated (Box 88)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 88)
    - Scripts, 1940-1956, undated, (6 folders) (Box 88)
    - Varieties magazine, 1944 (Box 88)
    - Viewpoint magazine, 1944-1945 (Box 88)
    - Writing workshop, 1942-1943 (Box 88)
- Ambassador Files, 1983-1995 (Box 89-97)
  Correspondence, clippings, official documents, and other material from Grunwald's term as United States ambassador to Austria.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Anchluss, 1988 (Box 89)
  - Antisemitism, 1987-1992 (Box 89)
  - Arms, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
  - Articles about Grunwald, 1987-1988 (Box 89)
  - Articles by Grunwald, 1989 (Box 89)
  - Auschwitz (Concentration camp), 1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian church, 1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian crime, 1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian criticism of the United States, 1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian domestic policy, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian electoral system, 1986 (Box 89)
  - Austrian foreign policy, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
  - Austrian history and literature, 1984-1988 (Box 89)
  - Austria-United States relations, 1988-1989 (Box 89)
  - Authority versus power, 1983 (Box 90)
  - Baker, James, 1989 (Box 90)
  - Bronfman, Edgar, 1987-1989 See also Classified (Box 90)
  - Bush, George H. W., 1989 (Box 90)
  - Capitalism, 1989-1990 (Box 90)
  - China, 1989 (Box 90)
  - Clipping books, 1987-1989, (8 folders) (Box 90)
  - Clippings, Austria, general, 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 91)
  - Clippings, United States, general, 1987-1989 (Box 91)
  - Commemorations, 1988-1989 (Box 91)
  - Communism, 1988-1989 See also Classified (Box 91)
  - Confirmation hearing, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 91)
  - Congratulatory notes, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 91)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 92)
  - Department of State, 1987-1991 See also Classified, (7 folders) (Box 92)
  - Department of State, White House, and congressional correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 92)
  - Economics, 1988-1989 (Box 92)
  - Education, 1987-1989 (Box 92)
  - Endism, 1989 (Box 92)
  - European Chiefs of Mission conference, Brussels, Belgium, 1989 See also Classified (Box 93)
  - European Community, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Grunwald, Louise, 1988-1989 See also Classified (Box 93)
  - Hrdlicka, Alfred, 1988 (Box 93)
  - International Cultural Policy Conference, panel discussion on culture and mass media, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Israel, 1988 (Box 93)
  - Journalism, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Judaism, 1988-1989 (Box 93)
  - Lainz hospital scandal, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Language, undated (Box 93)
  - Lauder, Ronald, 1986-1989 See also Classified (Box 93)
  - Lessing, Traudl, 1995 (Box 93)
  - Lucona trial, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Markus, Georg, 1989 (Box 93)
  - Mauthausen (Concentration camp), 1990-1995 (Box 93)
  - Memoranda of conversation, 1988-1989 See also Classified, (3 folders) (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, 1987-1989 (Box 93)
  - Nazi war crimes, 1987 (Box 93)
  - Noricum trial, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Peymann trial, 1988-1989 (Box 94)
  - Pope John Paul II visit to Austria, 1988 (Box 94)
  - Post-Cold War Europe, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Presentation of credentials, 1988 (Box 94)
  - Private trips, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 94)
  - Proksch, Udo, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Reactions to appointment, 1988-1989 (Box 94)
  - Refugees, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Resignation, 1989 (Box 94)
  - Rushdie, Salman, undated (Box 94)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1988 (Box 94)
  - Socialism, 1988-1989 (Box 94)
  - Swearing-in ceremony, 1987 See also Classified (Box 94)
  - United States domestic policy, 1988-1989 (Box 94)
  - United States Embassy, Vienna, Austria, 1987 See also Classified (Box 94)
  - United States Embassy, Vienna, Austria, guest books, 1988-1989, (4 folders) (Box 95)
  - United States foreign policy
    - Asia and the Middle East, 1988-1989 (Box 96)
    - Eastern Europe, 1988-1989 (Box 96)
    - Europe, 1988-1990 (Box 96)
    - General, 1982-1989, (3 folders) (Box 96)
    - Germany, 1988-1989 (Box 96)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1988-1989 (Box 96)
    - Soviet Union, 1987-1989 (Box 96)
  - United States politics, 1989 (Box 96)
  - Vienna, printed material, 1988-1989 See also Classified (Box 97)
  - Vranitzky, Franz, 1989 (Box 97)
  - Waldheim, Kurt, 1987-1995, undated See also Classified, (5 folders) (Box 97)
  - Zita, Empress of Austria, 1989 (Box 97)
- Time, inc. Editorial Files, 1941-2005 (Box 98-196)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1987 (Box 98-118)
    Correspondence and memoranda primarily with individuals outside the Time organization, but written in Grunwald’s capacity as a Time, inc. executive. This material consists chiefly of photocopies of documents held in the Time, inc. archive.
    Arranged chronologically then alphabetically therein.
    - 1950-1962, "A-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 98)
    - 1963-1964, "A-O" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 98)
    - 1963-1964, "P-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - 1965-1967, "A-S" miscellaneous, (13 folders) (Box 99)
    - 1965-1967, "T-Z" miscellaneous (Box 100)
    - 1968-1969, "A-M" miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 100)
    - 1968-1969, "N-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 101)
    - 1970-1972, "A-L" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 101)
    - 1970-1972, "M-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 102)
    - 1973, "A-M" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 102)
    - 1973, "N-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 103)
    - 1974, "A-K" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 103)
    - 1974, "L-Z" miscellaneous, (8 folders) (Box 104)
    - 1975, "A-B" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - 1975, "C-L" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box 105)
    - 1975, "M-Z" miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 106)
    - 1976, "A-W" miscellaneous, (10 folders) (Box 107)
    - 1977, "A-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 108)
    - 1978, "A-E" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 108)
    - 1978, "F-Z" miscellaneous, (8 folders) (Box 109)
    - 1979, "A-C" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 109)
    - 1979, "D-Z" miscellaneous, (12 folders) (Box 110)
    - 1980, "A-S" miscellaneous, (17 folders) (Box 111)
    - 1980, "T-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1981, "A-R" miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1981, "S-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 113)